Finding Aid for George William Cushing papers and sound recordings, 1942-1955
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George William Cushing papers and sound recordings 1942-1955
Cushing, George William, 1888-1968.
851077 Aa 2
News editor and vice president of Detroit, Michigan, radio station, WJR, moderator of radio program, "In Our Opinion". Correspondence, radio transcripts, scrapbooks, broadcast discs, and audio-tapes of discs; include material concerning career of Senator Arthur H. Vandenberg, the senatorial campaign of 1942 between Prentiss Brown and Homer Ferguson, and radio broadcasting in general.
1.3 linear feet
230 audiotapes in 9 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received from George Cushing (donor no. 3137 ) in 1955.
No further additions to the collection is expected.
The collection is open to research.
George W. Cushing, was born in Brighton, Michigan on November 25, 1888. In his career, he was both an advertising executive and a newsman. In 1909 he became a reporter on the Detroit News, also working while there in various editorial capacities. In 1912, he joined the Detroit office of the Taylor-Critchfield Advertising Agency; in 1914 he became first editor of the weekly publication of the Detroit Board of Commerce, The Detroiter.
In late 1915, Cushing was made advertising manager of the Federal Motor Truck Company, leaving here to join the Hudson Motor Car Company as advertising manager. He next helped to form the advertising agency of McKinney, Marsh and Cushing which handled advertising for the Ford Motor Company. After this he became first advertising director for the Graham-Paige Motors Corporation. He left this to become Detroit manager of Cosmopolitan Magazine for six years, and after that he was selected chief of information of the National Highway's Users Conference.
Cushing returned to Detroit in 1941 to join WJR as news editor and vice president. In 1942, he became moderator of "In Our Opinion" a weekly radio news program. He was assisted on many of the programs by regular panelists Detroit Free Press staff writers and columnists Adrian Fuller, Royce Howes, and William Coughlin. The program aired from 1942 to 1955 when Cushing retired. All together, he moderated 641 broadcasts, interviewing such guests as Senators Arthur Vandenberg and Homer Ferguson, Detroit Mayor Edward Jeffries.
In November 1954, Cushing began another series of program entitled "World Neighbors" which overlapped with "In Our Opinion" for a year.
The Cushing collection consists largely of sound recordings of a selection of the "In Our Opinion" radio program. There are also additional textual materials: clippings and other documents pertaining to the program and some transcriptions of particular programs.
The sound recordings of the "In Our Opinion" program were originally phonograph transmission discs. Nearly impossible to listen to because of their oversize format and the absence of appropriate players, the library applied for and received a grant in 1977 from the NHPRC to transfer a selection of the more than 600 discs onto reel-to-reel tapes. Many of the discs already showed signs of deterioration. The selection of what discs to preserve was based on the significance of the topics discussed and the importance of the interviewees. Among the guests were Senators Arthur Vandenberg and Homer Ferguson, automobile executive (later governor) George Romney, Congressman George Dondero, military historian General S.L.A. Marshall, political science Professor James K, Pollock, Governor Kim Sigler, Lowell Thomas, Thor Heyerdahl, Edward R. Murrow, and Episcopal Bishop Richard S. Emrich, among many others. Topics ranged from state and national politics, the impact of the war, foreign affairs, post-war re-conversion of the economy, and issues specific to Detroit and Michigan.
Subjects:
Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Cushing, George William, 1888-1968.; Detroit (Mich.); Ferguson, Homer, 1889-1982.; Journalists--Michigan--Detroit.; Radio broadcasting--Michigan--Detroit.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1942.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; WJR (Radio station: Detroit, Mich.)
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Detroit (Mich.)--History.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1942.; WJR (Radio station: Detroit, Mich.); Cushing, George William, 1888-1968.
Contributors: Sound Recordings
Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Dodero, George Anthony, 1883-1968.; Emrich, Richard S. M. (Richard Stanley Merrill), 1910-; Ferguson, Homer, 1888-1982.; Heyerdahl, Thor.; Marshall, S. L. A. (Samuel Lyman Atwood), 1900-1977.; Murrow, Edward R.; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968; Romney, George W., 1907-1995.; Sigler, Kim, b. 1894.; Thomas, Lowell, 1892-1981.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.
- Personal and Professional Papers
  - Biographical sketch (Box 1)
  - Arthur H. Vandenberg and his appearances on the radio 1945-1952 (Box 1)
  - Religious program "Guide Waves" 1953 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence regarding program, "World Neighbors" 1952-1954 (Box 1)
  - Letters received upon occasion of his retirement 1955 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts of "In Our Opinion" programs (Box 1)
  - Typescripts of "In Our Opinion" programs, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Newspaper accounts and other material relating to "In Our Opinion" programs 1942-1950, 4 volumes; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Newspaper accounts of the Prentiss Brown-Homer Ferguson Senatorial debate October 25, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper accounts of the two income tax programs February 27, 1944, March 5, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook containing teletype news releases of historical events (Box 2)
- In Our Opinion: recordings of programs, 7 in. reel-to-reel tapes; 7 1/2 ips
  - 1942
    - February 1, 1942 "The Defense of America from her Enemies Within" (Box 3)
      (Guest: John S. Bugas (Detroit Chief of the Federal Bureau of Investigation))
      (transcript of program in box 1)
    - February 8, 1942 "America's Attitude Toward the War" (Box 3)
      (Guest: Mayor Edward J. Jeffries, Jr. (Detroit))
    - April 26, 1942 "Mobilization of Manpower" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Hon. Paul V. McNutt (Chairman W.M.C.), Wendell Lund (Director of Mich. Unemployment Com.))
      (The surface of the disc from which this tape was made was poor)
    - July 5, 1942 "China Plight" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Miss Josephine A. Brown (Chung King), Chishau Lee (Vice-Consul General, Chicago), Prof. Alfred H. Kelly (Wayne University))
    - July 19, 1942 "The Doctor's Role in the War" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Lt. Col. John G. Slevin (Surgeon General's Office), Dr. C. D. Moll (Chairman, Wayne Co., P.A.A.))
    - July 26, 1942" (Box 3)
      (Should Prisoners be Permitted to Join Armed Forces" Guests: Dr. Garrett Heyns (Dir. State Corrections Comm.), Warden Joel R. Moore (Ionia Reformatory))
    - October 25, 1942 "The Ferguson-Brown Debate" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Judge Homer Ferguson, Senator Prentiss M. Brown)
      (The program was originally one hour, but much is unusable due to damage to the transcription discs)
  - 1943
    - March 7, 1943 "Monthly Cracker Barrel" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Professor Alfred H. Kelly (Wayne University), William Coughlin (Detroit Free Press), Duncan Moore (WJR))
    - March 14, 1943 "Percy Jones General Hospital, Battle Creek" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Pvt. Ralph Alvarado (Pfc.), Robert W. Baird (Pfc.), Jack S. Field (1st Lt.), Lakin Bowman (2nd Lt.), John J. Kelley, Jr. (Captain), Helena Clearwater)
    - July 18, 1943 "War Housing Problems: (Box 3)
      (Guests: Charles F. Edgecomb (Secretary, Detroit Housing Commission), Sherwood L. Reeder (Director, Federal Housing Authority), James E. Atkinson (President, Michigan Real Estate Association))
    - September 5, 1943 "Washington Newspaper Representatives at Mackinac Island", 2 tapes (Box 3)
      Guests: Raymond P. Brandt (St. Louis Post Dispatch), Esther Van Wagoner Tufty, Roscoe Drummond (Christian Science Monitor), Clifford Prevost (Free Press), Theodore C. Alford (Kansas City Star), Turner Catledge (New York Times)
    - September 12, 1943 "Should Women Be Drafted" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Mrs. Sprague Holden, Ruth Crane, Miss Marge Daugherty, Helen Bauer)
    - December 5, 1943 "Detroit's Part in the War Since Pearl Harbor" (Box 3)
      (Guests: George Romney (Automotive Council for War Production), Harvey Campbell (Detroit Board of Commerce))
      (The recorded surface has lifted off last 2/3 of first transcription disc, making its playing impossible. Therefore approx. 10 min. are missing)
  - 1944
    - March 19, 1944 "Juvenile Delinquency" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Rev. Father Flanagan (Boy's Town), Judge Paul W. Alexander)
    - July 23, 1944 "Visit to Owosso" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Mrs. George M. Dewey, Judge J.H. Collins, Earl Putnam, Clayton Potter, J. Evans Campbell, Mayor J. Edwin Ellis, Herman Dignan, Don Mitchell, William J. Coughlin (Detroit Free Press))
    - August 13, 1944 "Influence of Music" (Box 3)
      (Merle Evans and Beverly Kelley (Ringling Bros.), Valter Poole (Detroit Symphony Conductor), Graham Overgard (Band Conductor), Ozzie Nelson)
    - August 27, 1944 "Reconversion Problem" (Detroit and Washington). (Box 3)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson; Senator Carl Hatch, Representative George Dondero (At Detroit), George Romney)
      (The surface of the original disc was bad)
    - September 3, 1944 "Brazzaville" Radio Station. (Box 3)
      (Guests: Miss Helen Scott)
    - September 10, 1944 "Army Training in Schools" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Dr. David D. Henry (Wayne University), Dr. Eugene B. Elliott (Supt. Of Public Instruction))
      (The surface of the second half of the original disc was bad)
    - September 24, 1944 "Historians' Job in This War" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Milo F. Quaife, Dr. F. Clever Bald, Thomas I. Starr, Robert H. Larson)
    - October 15, 1944 "Problem of Automobile Parts" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Maj. Samuel Pace, George Otto, Ed Moore)
    - November 5, 1944 "Moral Issues of America" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Rev. G. Paul Musselman, B. E. Hutchinson, Dr. David Henry)
    - November 12, 1944 "Women Give Peace Views" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Mrs. John Orman, Mrs. Marian James, Mrs. Donald McGuire, Mrs. Bruce Douglas, Mrs. Eugene Woodruff)
    - November 26, 1944 "Should We Have Compulsory Military Training" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Dr. John Hannah, Warren Bow, Col. Owen Cleary, Rev. T. T. Brumbaugh)
    - December 3, 1944 "Bombing of Tokyo" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Singapore Joe Fisher, Rev. Father Edmund Horne)
    - December 10, 1944 "Naval Warfare" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Lt. John A. Walsh, Lt. Comm. D. McCowen, Leon Coulter (1st Cl. Mach. Mate))
    - December 17, 1944 "Michigan's Aviation Program" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Maj. S.B. Steers, Manfred Burleigh, Allen Dean, William M. Packer)
    - December 31, 1944 "New Year's Resolutions" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Edgar A. Guest, Malcolm Bingay)
  - 1945
    - January 7, 1945 "No-Strike Pledge" (Box 3)
      (Guests: August Scholle, W. T. Grant, Jess Ferrazza, Larry Yost)
    - January 14, 1945 "Eisenhower Group" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Capt. Robert B. Olson, Pfc. Sidney S. Winborne, Pfc. Frank C. Hall, Pfc. Virgil O. Barnes, Corp. Frank Christopian)
    - January 21, 1945 "Our Foreign Policies" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Senator Vandenberg)
    - January 28, 1945 "Work or Fight" (Box 3)
      (Guests: Harvey Campbell, Victor Reuther, Edward L. Cushman, John L. Lovett)
      (large portions missing due to broken discs)
    - March 4, 1945 "Detroit Strikes" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Under Secretary of War Robert P. Patterson, S/SGT. Odell Cassada, Sgt. Elmer K. Forrest)
      (first transcription disc was broken-approx. 8 min. missing from 2nd quarter of program)
    - March 11, 1945 "Factories Can't Employ Everybody" (Box 4)
      (Guests: C. Hartley Grattan, Robert F. C. Copeland)
    - March 25, 1945 "Red Cross" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Flint, Michigan, Lansing, Michigan, Port Huron, Michigan, Detroit, Michigan)
    - April 1, 1945 "Religion in the Lives of Front Line Fighters" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Rev. W. Vine Russell, Chaplain W. F. Burke, Chaplain R. Talbot Watkins, Staff Sgt. J.K. Brentford, Sgt. H. T. Eufill, Rev. Father Joseph E. Whelan)
    - April 8, 1945 "Back-to-the-Farm Move" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Harold Titus, Dean Samuel T. Dana, Prof. Kenneth C. McMurry)
    - April 15, 1945 "Reich Occupation" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Jack Bell)
    - April 22, 1945 "San Francisco Conference" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson, Senator Forrest C. Donnell)
    - May 6, 1945 "Detroit's Job After V-E Day" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson, Rear Adm. M.F. Schoeffel, Col. Raymond J. Kelly)
    - May 13, 1945 "Women's Role in Future" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Dr. Helen Reed, Bertha Lutz, Mrs. A. G. Skard, Mrs. Esther Van Wagoner Tufty, J. D. Callaghan)
    - May 20, 1945 "Nazi Brutality" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Malcolm Bingay)
    - May 27, 1945 "Survivors of USS Franklin" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Lt. Gordon Hassig, Machinists Mate George Phillips, Seaman Robert L. Tice, Coxswain Gerald Astourian)
    - June 3, 1945 "Food Problem in Detroit" Part 1. (Box 4)
      (Guests: Mrs. Walter K. Frost, Jimmie Asher, H.H. Varney, Owen Richards)
    - June 10, 1945 (Box 4)
    - "Food Problem in Detroit" Part 2. (Box 4)
      (Guests: Walter Carven, Mrs. George Ghere, George Thierwechter, Bliss Bowman, Jimmie Asher, Marshall Wells)
    - June 24, 1945 "Ball-Burton-Hatch Labor Bill" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Senator Joseph H. Ball, Senator Carl A. Hatch, Senator Harold H. Burton, Donald Richberg, Senator Homer Ferguson)
    - July 1, 1945 Governor's Conference (Mackinac Island) (Box 4)
      (Guests: Governor Harry F. Kelly, Governor Herbert B. Maw, Governor Earl Warren, Governor Ellis Arnall, Governor Raymond E. Baldwin, James Haswell)
      (The surface of the disc at the beginning was bad)
    - September 2, 1945 "Reconversion" (Box 4)
      (Guests: C E. Wilson, Senator Homer Ferguson, John A. Fry, Leo Donovan)
    - September 9, 1945 "Government's Views on Reconversion" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Louis C. Miriani, George Bowles, Arthur O'Shea)
    - September 16, 1945 "How Should We Treat the Japs?" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Dr. Thoburn T. Brumbaugh, James R. Young, J. B. Powell, Adrian Fuller)
    - September 30, 1945 "Post-War Conditions in Europe" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Congressman Chester E. Merrow, Congressman George A. Dondero, Congressman Bartel J. Jonkman, B. Dale Davis)
    - November 4, 1945 "State Editors' Views on Truman's First Six Months" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Nelson Brown, Harry E. Whitely, Webb McCall, Merle H. Dafoe, Owen C. Deatrick (broadcast from Mason, Michigan))
    - November 11, 1945 "Military Training for Peacetime American Youth" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Col. Dunlap C. Clark, Mrs. Lula E. Bachman, Rev. William J. Miller, Mrs. John K. Ormond, John Bethurum)
    - November 25, 1945 "President Truman's Proposed Health Bill (1)" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Dr. George I. McLellan, Rep. John Dingell, Nelson Cruikshank, Dr. Howard Schriver)
    - December 2, 1945 "President Truman's Proposed Health Bill (2)" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Arthur P. Johnson, Rep. John Dingell, Nelson Cruikshank, Dr. George I. McLellan)
    - December 16, 1945 "General Public on Truman's Proposed Health Bill (3)" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Leonard G. Bradley, Cleveland Lowry, John Stevenson, Mrs. Sidney Marwill, Henry J. Beyerle, Nicholas J. Schorn, Elizabeth Coulson)
  - 1946
    - January 13, 1946 "Air Future of Detroit and Michigan" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Col. Thomas G. Lamphier, Col. Floyd Evans, William A. Mara, Joseph W. Hance, Marc Williams, Curtis Haseltine)
    - February 3, 1946 "Does Michigan Need a Capital Punishment Law?" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Joseph E. Warner, Joel R. Moore, Louis B. Seltzer, Frank T. Cullitan)
    - March 17, 1946,"Food Problem in Europe" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson, Alfred D. Stedman, Fred A. Motz)
    - March 24, 1946 "Price Control" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Mrs. John W. Griffen, Mrs. A. C. Hughes, Frank X. Martel, Roy Robinson, Leo Donovan)
      (Bad cracks in first disc made part of program unplayable)
    - March 31, 1946 "Food Problems" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Dr. Ernest L. Anthony, Miss Winning S. Pendergast, John W. Piercey, Edward J. Frawley, John Frederick Muelh)
    - April 7, 1946 "Time Change" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Mrs. Guy Bedell, William L. Favinger, Charles Boyd, Chester Culver, John Considine, Sid Easton, M. W. Wisely, E.I. Besemer, August Scholle)
    - April 21, 1946 "Salvation Army" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Captain Tom Crocker, Maj. Mrs. Oscar Agre, Maurice McGriffin, George Clutter, Arthur Truesdale)
    - May 5, 1946 "A Decade of Decision" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Eric A. Johnston (President of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce)
    - May 12, 1946 "What Mothers Are Worrying About" (Box 4)
      (Guests: Louis Charbonneau, Sally Pickens, Patricia Hayes, Charles Anthony, Jr)
    - May 19, 1946 "I Am An American Day" (Box 4)
      (Guests: John Panchuk, Joseph Karasiewicz, Rudolph Herman, H.S. Derderian)
    - May 26, 1946 "Significance of the Golden Jubilee" (of the automobile). (Box 4)
      (Guests: Lt. Gen. William S. Knudsen, George Romney, Prentiss M. Brown, William E. Stirton, Leo Donovan)
    - June 2, 1946-Senator Arthur Vandenberg (Box 5)
    - June 2, 1946 "Golden Jubilee of the Automobile" (Box 5)
      (part 2)
    - June 16, 1946 "Father's Day" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Arthur Crampton, W. H. Hefelfinger, Bruce Tallman, Bruce McKay, Hugh McKay, Doyle Stemen, Carlos Stemen, Wm. Pittsley, Chas Pittsley, Arthur Crampton, Jr.)
    - June 23, 1946 "Controversial Problems of Youth" (Box 5)
      (Guests: David Anderson, Robert Neale, Robert Halbrook, Robert Baker, Bertrand Sandweiss, James Maynard)
    - June 30, 1946 "KAPPA Delegates Discuss OPA" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Nora Waln, Mrs. Gustave M. Heiss, Pattie Field O'Brien, Roxanna Jackson, Helen Bower)
    - July 7, 1946 "OPA" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Fred L. Riggin, Mayor Harry L. Gillow, Tom Ferris, Supt. Howard D. Crull, Lou A. Weil, Mrs. M.O. Hitchings, Mrs. Raymond Wurzel)
    - August 14, 1946 Senator Arthur Vandenberg (Box 5)
    - September 8, 1946 "What Is The Situation In Germany Today" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Dr. James K. Pollock)
    - September 15, 1946 "Shall Objects Of Historical Interest Be Preserved or Torn Down To Make Way For Modern Improvements" (Box 5)
      (Guests: George F. Emery, Commissioner Milton C. Selendar, Edgar P. Richardson, William Woolfenden)
    - September 22, 1946 "Can We Do Business With Russia?" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Dr. Charles Prince, Grant Arnold)
    - October 6, 1946 "Shall Criminals Be Punished or Treated For Their Behavior" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Austin MacCormick, Warden Walter Wallack, Dr. Miriam Van Waters, Dr. Robert M. Lindner, Hon. Ira W. Jayne)
    - October 19, 1946 Senator Arthur Vandenberg (Box 5)
    - October 20, 1946 "Discussion of the Three State Amendments to be Voted on in the November 5 Elections" (Box 5)
      (Guests: George Edwards, Charles C. Lockwood)
    - October 27, 1946 "The Inside Story on the Reporting of Radio News by Three Great Press Associations" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Tom O'Neil, Robert Brown, Phil Newsome)
    - November 10, 1946 "Is The Present Curriculum Of Our Schools Suited To The Present Day Needs Of Our Boys And Girls" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Dr. Eugene B. Elliott, Dr. Earl Kelly, Dr. Owen Emmons)
    - November 17, 1946 "Students Discuss The Present Curriculum Of Our Schools" Guests: Joe Cyr (Fordson High), Maureen Scanlon (Fordson High), Donald Muench (Northwestern High), Patricia Cawley (Northwestern High), Majorie Aiken (Highland Park Jr. College), Tom Frank (University of Michigan), Byron Williams (Wayne University), James Jones (Wayne University) (Box 5)
    - November 24, 1946 "Our Public Schools" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Mrs. Kathleen Lardie, Miss Margaret Mary Kerwin, Mrs. Laberyl Hayller, Miss Agnes Crow)
    - November 30, 1946 Senator Arthur Vandenberg (Box 5)
    - December 15, 1946 "Labor Court (Box 5)
      (" Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson)
  - 1947
    - January 5, 1947 "Religion in Affairs of Business and Politics" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Charles P. Taft (President of the Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America)
    - January 11, 1947, Senator Arthur Vandenberg, 2 tapes (Box 5)
    - January 12, 1947 "Law in Relation to Problems of Labor and Management" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Ernest Goodman, Leon Cousens, Frank Cooper, Max Veach)
    - January 19, 1947 "Labor Legislation" (Box 5)
    - January 26, 1947 "Labor Legislation" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Senator Joseph H. Ball, Nelson Cruikshank.)
      (The surface of the disc was bad)
    - February 8, 1947, Senator Arthur Vandenberg, 2 tapes (Box 5)
    - February 16, 1947 "Investigations by Governmental Committees" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson, Senator William F. Knowland)
    - February 23, 1947 "The Situation in China Today" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Rt. Rev. Quentin K. Y. Huang, Bishop of Kumming, Miss Maxine Westfall)
    - March 10, 1947 "State Budget" (Box 5)
      (Guests: John A. Perkins)
    - March 30, 1947 "Universal Military Training" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Lieutenant General Raymond S. McLain, Professor Alfred H. Kelly, Trainee Leonard A. Grushko)
    - April 6, 1947 "Detroit House of Correction" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Superintendent A. Blake Gillies, Miss Grace Travis, Mrs. Fern Dull, and members of the choir)
    - April 20, 1947 "Report on the German Situation" (Box 5)
    - April 28, 1947 "Report from Turkey and Greece" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson)
    - May 4, 1947 "College Campus Problems" (Box 5)
      (Guests: U-M student leaders, Richard Roder, Paul Harsha, Robert Wiese, Haskel Coplin)
    - May 11, 1947 "Infiltration of Communists in the United States" (Box 5)
      (Guests: Frederick Woltman, Charles Hasperhoven)
    - June 8, 1947-"Michigan State Class of 1912 35th Reunion" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Mrs. Thomas Gunson, Ralph Goodell, C. H. Dickinson, H. Lee Bancroft, E. E. Hotchin, B. P. Pattison, R. B. Delvin, Bess Howe Geagley, Leon C. Exelby, Glen O. Stewart)
    - June 15, 1947 "Turkey" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Mrs. Fahrinnisa Seden, Dr. Roy D. McClure)
    - June 29, 1947 "The Family Doctor" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Dr. William G. Wight, Dr. Frederick B. Wight, Mayor John Kaatz, Frank Andre, Fred Andre (grandson of above), Clarence Reed (farmer), Mrs. George Barth, D. A. McIntyre (Detroit), Mrs. Dora Martin, Miss Pearl McDonald, George Cavanaugh, John Patterson, Mary McCabe (nurse), Mina Mackman (nurse))
    - July 6, 1947 "Traffic Safety (Mich. State Police)" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Capt. C. J. Scavarda, Sergeant C. F. Van Blankensteyn, Mr. Orrin Lucas, Sergeant William Bouck, Dispatcher McBride, (Reports from: Jackson, Rockwood, Detroit, Bay City, State Trooper at Pinconning))
    - July 20, 1947 "Father Flanagan's Report on Japan" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Father Flanagan)
    - September 4, 1947 Senator Arthur Vandenberg (Box 6)
    - September 21, 1947 "The Hillsdale County Fair" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Harry B. Kelley, Lester Rogers, Sherman Young, Miss Blanche Wolcott, Ivan Maystead, Blair Woodman, Marshall Wells)
    - September 28, 1947 "Hickory Corners" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Governor Kim Sigler, Oscar Harrington, C. F. Rennels, Vere Williams, Ralph Starring, C. M. McCrary)
    - October 5, 1947 "Candidates for Mayor of Detroit" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Mayor Edward J. Jeffries, Jr., Eugene Van Antwerp, Gerald Adams, Herman Benson, George O. Cornell, Howard Lerner, Joseph J. Mogor, Alfred C. Semande)
    - October 12, 1947 "Desperate Situation in Europe" (Box 6)